<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>经济学 on 串串的杂七杂八</title><link>https://blog.acdzh.ltd/tags/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6/</link><description>Recent content in 经济学 on 串串的杂七杂八</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><copyright>Copyright (c) 2020. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 22:32:20 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.acdzh.ltd/tags/%E7%BB%8F%E6%B5%8E%E5%AD%A6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>软件工程经济学笔记 Ch3 - Core Principles and Features of Software Platform</title><link>https://blog.acdzh.ltd/tec/2020-05/se_eco_note_3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 22:32:20 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.acdzh.ltd/tec/2020-05/se_eco_note_3/</guid><description>lecture - SEE.ch03.lecture.pdf chinese: https://book.mihua.net/book/50/50832/65684.html Goal Understanding ecosystem, platform lifecycles using dominant designs, S-curves, and diffusion curves. Platform properties: multi-sidedness, network effects, multi-homing, architecture, and governance. Platform dynamics: tipping, locking-in, competitive durability, and envelopment. How platform businesses differ from product and service business. Why platforms need a mindset different from products and services. 3.1 核心概念 Core Concepts 生态系统 Ecosystem An environment consists of all</description></item><item><title>软件工程经济学笔记 ch2 - Demand and Supply</title><link>https://blog.acdzh.ltd/tec/2020-04/se_eco_note_2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 11:15:51 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.acdzh.ltd/tec/2020-04/se_eco_note_2/</guid><description>lecture - SEE.ch02.lecture.pdf Goal Distinguish between quantity demanded and demand, and explain what determines demand. Distinguish between quantity supplied and supply, and explain what determines supply. Explain how demand and supply determine price and quantity in a market, and explain the effects of changes in demand and supply. 2.1 Demand 2.1.1 Law of Demand price down -&amp;gt; demand up 2.1.2 Demand Schedule &amp;amp; Demand Curve Demand: the relationship between the</description></item><item><title>软件工程经济学笔记 ch1 - Introduction of Software Engineering Economy</title><link>https://blog.acdzh.ltd/tec/2020-04/se_eco_note_1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 23:29:49 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.acdzh.ltd/tec/2020-04/se_eco_note_1/</guid><description>lecture - SEE.ch01.lecture.pdf Goal Define economics and explain the questions that economists try to answer. Explain the kinds of questions that define the economic way of thinking. 1.1 Definition &amp;amp; Ques 经济问题 &amp;lt;- 人的需求 &amp;gt; 可用资源 Scarcity 稀缺 原因: 需求 &amp;gt; 资源 =&amp;gt; 需要替代方案. Economics Defined 经济学定</description></item></channel></rss>